Professional Profile

Insatiably curious coder with 3 years experience building web applications (primarily in Ruby on Rails and React/Alt). Passionate about fixing bugs and optimizing code. Shares her love of code through conference talks and YouTube videos.

EXPERIENCE

Developer, Flatiron School

(2014 - Present)

- Led development efforts from product spec through completion for blogging, public lesson pages and new course features on Learn.co
- Collaborated with product managers, QA engineers, labs team developers, and other stakeholders to derive an appropriate implementation strategy and ship features on time
- Built new onboarding flow which significantly reduced sign up friction for new students using Ruby on Rails and React
- Implemented blogging feature to increase technical writing from students using Ruby on Rails, Backbone, Marionette and the Github API
- Designed database schema and wrote recurring tasks to process student progress data and determine approaching eligibility for graduation in order to properly notify students and support staff
- Utilized Object-Oriented CSS to update Learn.co app with consistent look (reducing amount of CSS by 70%)
- Boosted discoverability of Learn by creating keyword-rich, public-facing lesson pages
- Participated in code reviews and gave presentations and demos to team to share knowledge of the codebase
- Gave lectures on jQuery and Learning from Failure to in-person immersive Flatiron students while serving a three-month rotation on the education team
- Wrote blog posts for the Flatiron School blog, Uncubed and Quora to foster a learning community for prospective and current students
- Worked with business stakeholders to create SQL-based charts in Periscope to allow regular reporting on key performance indicators

Account Manager – Search & Social, OMD Entertainment (2012 - 2014)

- Planned and managed implementation of North American-targeted search and social marketing campaigns for Disney's DVD releases
- Spearheaded keyword strategy that boosted conversions by 15% and lead to adoption across all titles being sold with a digital format
- Implemented video campaigns on YouTube using inSearch, inStream and remarketing

Search Marketing Manager, MatchCraft

(2005 - 2012)

- Coordinated with cross-functional team of engineers and client representatives to transition live programs without disruption of ad delivery
- Partnered with clients across nine countries (involving five languages) to identify needs and develop or refine online marketing programs to meet those needs
- Implemented taxonomy changes which improved on-time fulfillment by 20%
- Grew largest program by 43% without increasing size of team working on account
- Streamlined team processes reducing account operating costs by 15%

Public Speaking & Writing

Conference Talks

- Will it Inject: SQL Injection and Active Record Rails Conference https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2GHWAYys1is
- Diversity in Tech: Beyond the Hiring Process Ruby Conference AU -https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2016-1489/diversity-in-tech-it-s-about-more-than-just-the-hiring-process-by-jess-rudder-1944

Video Presentations

Videos on Code Topics - CompChomp - https://youtube.com/compchomp

Books

Ruby in *The Librarian's Introduction to Programming Languages: A LITA Guide* (pp. 27-40).
 Lanham, MA: Rowman & Littlefield

EDUCATION

Continuing/self-directed learning

- Emphases: critical thinking and technology
- Courses of study: formal logic, philosophy, artificial intelligence, drawing

Flatiron School

Full stack web development utilizing Ruby on Rails and JavaScript

New York University

B.A. Drama with training in stage productions, public speaking and literature

INTERESTS

general aviation (licensed), ultra running, cooking, robotics, cycling